嗨，我是天使·科雷亚（Angel Corre），我认为自己是团队合作者，一个人...
Hi, I'm Angel Correa and I consider myself a team player, a guy ...
Hola, soy Ángel Correa y me considero un jugador de equipo, un tipo...
熟悉，总是为您的战斗。
familiar and always fight for yours.
familiar y que siempre lucha por lo suyo.
首先感谢Angelito接收我们。
First thanks Angelito for receiving us.
Primero gracias Angelito por recibirnos.
我们想做这篇笔记，尤其是因为您的职业生涯中没有很多笔记，您并没有说话，太好了。
We wanted to make this note, especially because there are not many notes of yours in your career, you are not talking, so good.
teníamos ganas de hacer esta nota, sobre todo porque no hay muchas notas tuyas en tu carrera, no sos de hablar, así que bueno.
这是值得的，我们为此感到高兴，谢谢。
It is worth double, we are happy for that, thank you.
Vale el doble, estamos contentos por eso, gracias.
不客气，我很高兴与您进行采访。
You're welcome, a pleasure for me to do the interview with you.
De nada, un gusto también para mí hacer la entrevista con ustedes.
而且您也在家里。
And you are also at home.
Y además estás en tu casa.
在这个培训期间，他们在这个城市的这个地方已经有很多年了。
They are so many years in this place, in this city, in this training period.
Son tantos años en este lugar, en esta ciudad, en este periodo de entrenamiento.
是的，事实是，我感觉到了我的房子。
Yes, the truth is that I feel the Atlético as my house.
Sí, la verdad que sí, que siento al Atlético como mi casa.
没什么，很高兴在这里收到它。
And nothing, a pleasure to receive it here.
Y nada, un placer recibirlo acá de ustedes.
您住多少年？
How many years are you living here?
¿Cuántos años son que vivís acá?
我来自圣洛伦佐（San Lorenzo），于2014年到达。
I arrived in 2014 when I came from San Lorenzo.
Llegué en 2014 cuando vine de San Lorenzo.
必须从内心运作才能签署的情况。
The situation that had to operate from the heart to be able to sign.
la situación esa de que me tuvieron que operar de corazón para poder ficharme.
我呆在那里，我一直在这里，在俱乐部。
And there I stayed and I was always here, in the club.
Y ahí ya me quedé y siempre estuve acá, en el club.
也就是说，您在这里住了11年。
That is, you lived 11 years here.
Es decir que viviste 11 años acá.
在罗萨里奥（Rosario），你住了几个？
In Rosario, how many did you live?
En Rosario, ¿cuántos viviste?
我去了罗萨里奥（Rosario）的12年，我去了布宜诺斯艾利斯（Buenos Aires）住在圣洛伦佐（San Lorenzo）养老金。
And I went to the 12 years of Rosario, I went to Buenos Aires to live at the San Lorenzo pension.
y me fui a los 12 años de Rosario, me fui a Buenos Aires a vivir a la pensión de San Lorenzo.
我到了12到18岁。
And there I was from 12 to 18 that I came here.
y ahí estuve de 12 a 18 que ahí me vine para acá.
精英团队中不应该有那么多球员的时间太多，因为如果您愿意，我们正在谈论前十名。
There should not be so many players so much time in an elite team, because we are talking about Top 10, if you want, team teams.
No debe haber tantos futbolistas así tanto tiempo en un equipo de elite, porque estamos hablando de Top 10, si querés, de equipos del mundo.
是的，事实是，如果您想的话，有些好。
Yes, the truth is that good, if you think, there are some.
Sí, la verdad que bueno, si te pone a pensar, hay algunos.
但是不，这是一个现实，玩家通常不长这么长时间
But no, it is a reality that players are not usually so long
pero no, es una realidad que los jugadores no suelen estar tanto tiempo
在同一支团队中，他们总是改变，但是，嘿，正如我之前所说，我注意到它是我的房子，我总是感到非常...
In the same team they always change, but hey, as I said before, I notice it as my house, I always felt very ...
En un mismo equipo siempre van cambiando, pero bueno, como te decía antes, la noto como mi casa, siempre me sentí muy...
非常亲爱的这里，这就是为什么我已经这么多年了。
Very dear here and that's why I have been so many years.
muy querido acá y por eso llevo tantos años.
而另一件事总是与同一位技术人员在一起，这也很少见。
And another thing, always with the same technician, that is also rare.
Y otra cosa, siempre con el mismo técnico, eso también es rarísimo.
是的，我们是几个在这里携带很多的同伴。
Yes, we are several companions who carry a lot here.
Sí, somos varios compañeros que llevamos acá mucho.
很多年，也是我到达之前的Cholo。
Many years, and well, with Cholo too, that he is before I arrive.
muchos años, y bueno, con el Cholo también, que él está antes de que yo llegue.
因为有人说，莱蒂是欧洲的阿根廷队，因为这笔款项的数量。
Because there is talk that Lety is the Argentine team in Europe for the amount there is.
porque se habla de que la Lety es el equipo argentino en Europa por la cantidad que hay.
但是，原始的，第一个，到达的人，是最古代的那个，你是。
But the original, the first, the one who arrived, the one that has the most antiquity, you are.
Pero el original, el primero, el que llegó, el que más antigüedad tiene, sos vos.
您是否告诉您的阿根廷同伴。
You tell your Argentine companions or not.
Se lo decís a tus compañeros argentinos o no.
好吧，我认为当我到达时，我也只是在祖巴，他已经去了那里。
And well, I think when I arrived I was just in Zuba too, that he was already going there.
Y bueno, creo que cuando llegué estaba justo en Zuba también, que ahí ya se estaba yendo.
奥古斯托，越野，盖塔恩通过。
Augusto, Vieto, Gaitán passed.
Pasó Augusto, Vieto, Gaitán.
事实是，我们不是在谈论这一点。
The truth is that we are not talking about that.
La verdad es que no hablamos de eso.
但是，是的，被阿根廷包围总是很好。
But yes, it is always good to be surrounded by Argentines.
Pero sí, siempre está bueno estar rodeado de argentinos.
戈文曾是乌拉圭，乔斯玛（Josema）已经呆了很长时间了，真相...
Uruguayan that Godín was, there was Josema who had been for a long time, the truth that ...
de Uruguayo que estaba Godín, estaba Josema también que llevaba mucho tiempo, la verdad que...
一个不错的小组形成了。
That a nice group is formed.
que se forma un lindo grupo.
您经历了所有的比赛，联赛获胜，国际冠军赢得了冠军，这也很困难。
And you went through all, leagues won, international championships won, which is also difficult.
Y pasaste por todas, ligas ganadas, campeonatos internacionales ganados, que también es difícil.
在这个季节的某个时刻，很少见。
And in some moments this season was rare.
y en algunos momentos esta temporada fue rara.
因为可以说他们做得很好，因为他们与一切作战，但可以这么说，但是还有几个星期。
Because the truth can be said that they did well because they fought everything, but there were also a few weeks, so to speak.
porque la verdad que se puede decir que les fue bien porque pelearon todo, pero también hubo unas semanas trágicas, por decirlo de alguna manera.
是的，事实是。
Yes, the truth is.
Sí, la verdad que sí.
当一个季节开始时，当您获得如此巨大的幻觉时，坏事
Bad when you get such great illusion when a season starts with
Mal cuando te haces una ilusión tan grande cuando arranca una temporada con los
签约到了，朱利安和更多同伴到了。
The signings that arrived, that Julian and several more companions arrived.
los fichajes que llegaron, que llegó Julián y varios compañeros más.
他们赢得了比赛的胜利，为球队提供了更多。
They come with that wins to compete, to give the team more.
que vienen con esa gana de competir, de darle más al equipo.
采取该步骤获得一些标题。
To take that step to get some title.
para dar ese paso para conseguir algún título.
突然间，您发现比赛很少，并且不为之奋斗...
And when suddenly you find that there are few games and do not fight for ...
y cuando de repente te encontrás que quedan pocos partidos y ya no peleas por...
几乎没有，低迷是非常明显的。
For almost none, the downturn is very noticeable.
por casi ninguno, el bajón ese se nota muchísimo.
在这里这么多年之后，不知道您的未来和其他人将是什么。
After so many years here, without knowing what will be of your future and others.
después de tantos años acá, sin saber qué va a ser de tu futuro y demás.
它日复一日地怀旧吗？
Does it give you nostalgia day to day?
¿Te da nostalgia el día a día?
他去了城市，你的房子，你习惯的东西，因为玩家的生活有时是...
He goes to the city, your house, what you are used to, because the life of the player is that sometimes ...
va a la ciudad, tu casa, lo que estás acostumbrado, porque la vida del futbolista es que a veces...
您有一个连根拔起的，您将出去另一个城市，失去与家人在一起的一切。
You have a uprooting one to the other, you will go out to another city and lose all that you had with a family behind.
tenés un desarraigo de un minuto al otro, vas a salir a otra ciudad y perdés todo eso que tenías con una familia detrás.
您是每天怀旧还是如何？
Are you living nostalgia day by day or how are you?
¿Estás viviendo con nostalgia el día a día o cómo estás?
事实是，我来与家人和我的妻子交谈很多。
And the truth is that I come talking a lot to my wife, with my family.
Y la verdad que lo vengo hablando mucho con mi mujer, con mi familia.
与我的女儿一起，这是一个现实，这可能发生在我身上。
With my daughters, which is a reality and that can happen to me.
con mis hijas, que es una realidad y que puede pasarme.
这就是为什么我现在尝试这些游戏的剩余内容。
That is why I try now what remains of these games.
Por eso trato de disfrutar ahora lo que queda de estos partidos.
培训，然后进行...
of the training and then go with ...
de los entrenamientos y después ir con...
借助俱乐部世界杯的所有电池，当您完成它时，看看我的未来将是什么。
With all the batteries of the Club World Cup too and then when you finish that to see what will be of my future.
con todas las pilas del Mundial de Clubes también y ya después cuando termine eso ver qué va a ser de mi futuro.
你知道你想要什么吗？
Do you know what you want?
¿Sabés qué querés?
是的，我想要的，好吧，我已经和Cholo交谈了...
Yes, what I want, well I've talked to Cholo and with ...
Sí, lo que quiero, bueno ya lo he hablado con el Cholo y con...
与俱乐部一起他们尊重我，并且总是知道
With the club they respect me and know that always
con el club ellos me respetan y saben que siempre
我总是在这里交付所有东西来帮助团队，我总是把所有东西都放在这里。
I always delivered everything here to help the team, I always put everything.
Siempre entregué todo acá de mí para ayudar al equipo, siempre puse todo.
我总是优先考虑团队。
I always prioritized the team before.
Siempre prioricé el equipo antes.
我知道并理解我，他们给了我自由。
That I know and understand me, they gave me freedom.
que yo, saben y me entienden, me dieron la libertad.
决定我想为未来做什么，所以我告诉他们
to decide what I want to do for my future, so I told them that
de decidir qué quiero hacer para mi futuro, por eso les comentaba que
我想完成这六个左派比赛。
that I want to finish these six left games.
que quiero terminar estos seis partidos que quedan.
尽力而为，像我往常一样帮助团队，在俱乐部世界杯上也一样，希望享受它，希望...
Do your best, help the team as I always do and in the club World Cup the same, enjoy it, hopefully ...
hacerlo lo mejor posible, ayudar al equipo como siempre lo hago y en el Mundial de Club igual, disfrutarlo, ojalá que...
我们可以赢得它，然后我会看到。
that we can win it and then I will see.
que lo podamos ganar y ya después voy a ver.
因为我也认为，当它们在任何地方被命名时必须集中在中心，这并不容易。
Because I also imagine that one has to be centered when they are named everywhere and it is not easy.
porque también imagino que uno tiene que estar centrado cuando se lo nombran todos lados y no es fácil.
是的，是的，我之前评论过
Yes, yes, I commented before
Sí, sí, les comentaba antes que
一些消息传来，就像我已经与另一支球队有一个预先介绍，那就是谎言。
Some news comes out like I already have a pre -agreement with another team and that is lies.
salen algunas noticias como que yo ya tengo un preacuerdo con otro equipo y eso son mentiras.
与任何人进行预先介绍。
A pre -agreement with anyone.
Un preacuerdo con nadie.
像我往常一样，我集中精力继续进步。
I am concentrated, as I always did, in the team, to continue improving.
Yo estoy concentrado, como siempre lo hice, en el equipo, en seguir mejorando.
那留下了墨西哥吗，是谎言吗？
Did that leave Mexico, is it a lie?
¿Eso salió de México, es mentira?
是的，因为我与任何团队没有任何预先介绍。
Yes, because I don't have any pre -agreement with any team.
Sí, porque yo no tengo ningún preacuerdo con ningún equipo.
完美的。
Perfect.
Perfecto.
我仍然与Atlético有一年的合同，直到2026年，我才有合同。
I still have a year of contract with Atlético, which I have a contract until 2026.
Todavía me queda un año de contrato con el Atlético, que tengo contrato hasta 2026.
我遇到了尼尔·安吉尔（Niel Angel），他告诉我他想续签我。
I have met with Niel Angel, he told me that he wants to renew me.
Me he reunido con Niel Angel, me ha dicho que me quiere renovar.
Cholo告诉我他对我的工作感到满意。
Cholo told me he is happy with my work.
El Cholo me dijo que está contento con mi trabajo.
这了解我，并决定我对我的感觉更好。
that understands me and decides what I feel is better for me.
que me entiende y que decida lo que yo siento que es mejor para mi.
然后，我们将不得不等待俱乐部单位，这很明显。
Then we will have to wait for the club unit, that is very clear.
Entonces habrá que esperar la unidad de clubes, eso está clarísimo.
然后决定。
And then the decision.
Y después la decisión.
在提到的俱乐部中，例如在阿根廷出现。
Among the clubs that are mentioned, for example in Argentina, River appears.
Dentro de los clubes que se mencionan, por ejemplo en Argentina, aparece River.
您是否认为是否有可能在阿根廷河上玩？
Do you see a possibility of playing at the Argentinian River or not?
¿Ves viable una posibilidad de jugar en el Argentinian River o no?
我不知道，当时我必须在那里做。
I don't know, I would have to do there at the time.
No lo sé, tendría que ver ahí en el momento.
它使它感到高兴，因为它是一个很棒的俱乐部。
It makes it happy because it is a great club.
lo pone contento porque es un grandísimo club.
我很幸运见到加拉多，这似乎是一个宏伟的
I was lucky to meet Gallardo, it seems like a magnificent
Tuve la suerte de conocerlo a Gallardo, me parece un magnífico
教练，我也知道几个男孩也在团队中。
Coach, I know several boys who are there on the team too.
entrenador, conozco a varios chicos que están ahí en el equipo también.
但是，我不能告诉你为什么我不知道会发生什么。
But well, I can't tell you why I don't know what will happen.
Pero bueno, no te puedo decir porque no sé qué va a pasar.
但是加拉多打电话，坚持吗？
But Gallardo calls, insists?
¿Pero Gallardo llama, insiste?
不，我没有和他说话，不。
No, I didn't talk to him, no.
No, no hablé con él, no.
所以我不知道那个谣言是否出来，因为没有人与我沟通。
So I don't know if that rumor comes out because nobody communicated with me.
Así que tampoco sé si es cierto ese rumor que sale porque a mí no se comunicó nadie conmigo.
而且，说到阿根廷，您的心脏也分裂了，对吗？
And, apart, speaking of Argentina, you have as the heart divided too, right?
Y, aparte, hablando de Argentina, vos tenés como el corazón dividido también, ¿no?
一个在您留在后代的地方，即圣洛伦佐（San Lorenzo），另一个是俱乐部。
One in the place where you remained for posterity, which is San Lorenzo, another for the club.
uno en el lugar donde quedaste para posteridad, que es San Lorenzo, otro por el club.
您多次承认您跟随他，他将其暂停为Rosario中央。
You confessed many times that you follow him, that he suspends as Central Rosario.
confesaste muchas veces que lo seguís, que sos hincha como Rosario Central.
我更多地问这是您的人生计划，而不是在团队中再次参加比赛的事实。
I ask this more as your life plan, not the fact of playing again in a team.
Esto te lo pregunto más como plan de vida tuyo, no el hecho de volver a jugar en un equipo.
您是否觉得在某个时候仍然活跃，再次住在阿根廷？
Do you feel like at some point, while you are still active, to live again in Argentina?
¿Tenés ganas de en algún momento, mientras estés en actividad todavía, volver a vivir en Argentina?
在一个团队中玩，或者事实是您关闭的阶段，您在另一个阶段，并且没有考虑。
Play in a team or it is something that the truth is a stage that you closed, you are in another and do not think about it.
jugar en algún equipo o es algo que la verdad es una etapa que cerraste, estás en otra y no lo pensás.
从圣洛伦佐（San Lorenzo）出发，我没有机会谈论太多的事实。
From San Lorenzo the truth that I did not have the opportunity either to talk much.
De San Lorenzo la verdad que no tuve la oportunidad tampoco de hablar mucho.
而且许多人也不知道。
And many people don't know it either.
y mucha gente no lo sabe tampoco.
当我离开那里时，我离开了...
When I left there I left ...
Yo cuando me fui de ahí me fui...
当时的领导不好，因为
bad with the leadership that was at that time because
mal con la dirigencia que estaba en ese momento porque
我来这里做医学评论以签署自己，我不得不参加Libertadores的半决赛。
I came here to do the medical review to sign myself and I had to play the semifinal of the Libertadores.
Vine acá a hacer la revisación médica para ficharme y tenía que volver a jugar la semifinal de la Libertadores.
如果我们度过了决赛，我会发现我的心脏出来的问题。
If we spent the final and I find the problem that my heart came out.
si pasábamos la final y me encuentro con el problema que me salió el corazón.
当时那里唯一关心的是卖我，我不知道我是否要回到...
And the only thing that cared there at that time was to sell me and I didn't know if I was going back to ...
y lo único que le importó ahí en ese momento a la dirigencia era en venderme y yo no sabía si iba a volver a...
要踢足球，我才18岁。
To play football, I was 18 years old.
a jugar al fútbol, tenía 18 años recién.
这就是最伤害我的原因。
And that is what hurt me the most.
y eso es lo que más me dolió.
永远不要谈论圣洛伦佐，但我对所有人都保持着美好的回忆。
Never speak of San Lorenzo, but I keep a great memory of all people.
Nunca hable más de San Lorenzo, pero guardo un grandísimo recuerdo de toda la gente.
在我住在那里的那几年，我不会忘记，因为我到了12年，他们给了我退休金，他们给了我食物，教育。
Of the years I lived there, I do not forget because I arrived with 12 years, they gave me a pension, they gave me food, education.
de los años que viví ahí, no me olvido porque yo llegué con 12 años, me dieron pensión, me dieron comida, educación.
很多事情，事实是我有一个巨大的爱。
Many things and the truth is that I have a huge love.
Muchísimas cosas y la verdad que le tengo un cariño enorme.
我很幸运能成为比赛的冠军。
I was lucky to be champion of the tournament.
Tuve la suerte de ser campeón del torneo.
赢得解放者，所以很多人总是给我写信给我圣洛伦佐
win the liberators, so there are many people always writes to me San Lorenzo that
ganar la Libertadores, así que por ahí mucha gente siempre me escribe San Lorenzo que
我什么也没说，但这是针对这个问题的。
I never say anything, but it was for that subject.
que nunca digo nada, pero era por ese tema.
也就是说，您将人们分开，对俱乐部充满问题。
That is, you separate people, love to the club with the problem.
O sea, separás a la gente, el cariño al club con el problema.
我知道人们也爱我。
I know that people love me too.
Yo sé que la gente me quiere, yo también.
我是一个感激的人。
I am a grateful person.
Yo soy una persona agradecida.
我感谢您今天在Atlético离开圣洛伦佐（San Lorenzo）。
I thank you that today I am here in Atlético for leaving San Lorenzo.
Le agradezco que hoy en día estoy acá en el Atlético por salir de San Lorenzo.
在今天非常活跃的网络中。
and in the networks that are very active today.
y en las redes que hoy son muy activas.
中心坚持，消息传达给您。
Central insists, messages reach you.
De central te insiste, te llegan mensajes.
是的，当时，当我首先首次亮相时，他们问我那是什么照片，我去了。
Yes, also, well, at the time, when I debuted in First, they asked me what picture it was and I went.
Sí, también, bueno, en su momento, cuando debuté en primera, me preguntaron de qué cuadro era y yo fui.
真诚我说我就像我的整个罗萨里奥中心家庭一样。
Sincere I said I am like my whole family of Rosario Central.
sincero dije yo soy como toda mi familia hincha de Rosario Central.
每个人都知道那时在圣洛伦佐。
And everyone knew that then in San Lorenzo.
y eso lo sabía todo el mundo en ese entonces en San Lorenzo.
关于成为粉丝，您想在中心玩吗？还是您无法保证的？
And regarding being a fan, would you like to play in Central or is it something you can't promise?
Y con respecto a ser hincha, ¿te gustaría jugar en central o es algo que no puedes prometer?
不，是的，是的，很明显我想要。
No, yes, yes, obvious I would like.
No, sí, sí, obvio que me gustaría.
我一直在这里已经有很多年了，这让我感到惊讶。
I have always been here for so many years that it is surprised.
Siempre llevo tantos años acá en España que se extraña.
阿根廷足球，我们的足球与其他一切都不同。
Argentine football, that our football is different from everything else, what is lived there.
El fútbol argentino, que nuestro fútbol es diferente a todo lo demás, lo que se vive ahí.
在法庭上，它与其他国家不同。
On a court it is different from other countries.
en una cancha es diferente a otros países.
而且，如果一个人拥有尽可能多的爱，例如，他看到一个体育场和巨大的Arroyito，一件事在外面说话，另一件事是在里面看到他。
And, apart, if one has as much love, he sees a stadium as the giant Arroyito, for example, one thing speaks outside and another thing is to see him inside.
Y, aparte, si uno tiene tanto cariño, ve un estadio como el Gigante Arroyito, por ejemplo, una cosa habla afuera y otra cosa es verlo adentro.
我的家人，我想你有人，中央兄弟，中央朋友...
And that your family, that I imagine you have people, central brothers, friends of Central ...
y que tu familia, que me imagino tenés gente, hermanos de central, amigos de central...
想象一下，在那里，带中央衬衫为您来说很特别。
Imagine there, with the central shirt, be special for you.
Imaginarte ahí, con la camiseta de centrales, ser especial para vos.
是的，是的，显而易见。
Yes, yes, obvious.
Sí, sí, obvio.
是的，我有很多家人和朋友。
Yes, I have many family and friends.
Sí, tengo muchos familiares y amigos.
我也有反对。
I also have the contra.
También tengo de la contra.
我的妻子是纽威尔。
My wife is Newell.
Mi mujer es de Newell.
啊，是吗？
Ah, yes?
¿Ah, sí?
是的，是的，我们有一个部门，但是嘿，没问题。
Yes, yes, we have a division, but hey, no problem.
Sí, sí, tenemos ahí una división, pero bueno, no hay problema.
她陪着我，她不会有问题。
She accompanies me, she will not have problems.
Ella me acompaña, no va a tener problemas.
但是，我们将其留给以后。
But well, we leave that for later.
Pero bueno, eso lo dejamos para más adelante.
希望可以给予它。
Hopefully, hopefully it can be given.
Ojalá, ojalá que se pueda dar.
我可以去，你可以变得健康，竞争。
I can go, you can get well, compete.
pueda ir, pueda llegar bien, competir.
我今年30岁，我还很年轻。
I am 30 years old, I feel young yet.
Tengo 30 años, me siento joven todavía.
例如，你必须着急。
Di Maria you have to hurry, for example.
A Di María lo tenés que apurar, por ejemplo.
我希望他很亲密，他真的想走，他很亲密，但是嘿。
I wish he was close, he really wanted to go, he was close, but hey.
Ojalá él estuvo cerca, tuvo muchas ganas de ir, estuvo cerca, pero bueno.
我认为，对于您来说，您无法付出的几个，但是很好。
I think that for several there you could not give, but well.
Creo que por varios temitas ahí no se pudo dar, pero bueno.
我希望他也可以去享受和他的家人，他们都是罗萨里奥（Rosario）。
I hope he can go and enjoy and his family too, who are all from Rosario.
Ojalá que él pueda ir y disfrutar y su familia también, que son todos de Rosario.
事实是，阿根廷足球会做得很好。
The truth is that Argentine football is going to do very well.
La verdad es que le va a hacer muy bien al fútbol argentino.
你关注阿根廷足球吗？
Do you follow Argentine football?
¿Seguís el fútbol argentino?
您如何在可能的情况下看到游戏或变得复杂？
How do you see games here when you can or get complicated?
¿Como espectadores de acá ves partidos cuando podés o se complica?
随着时间表有时，它很复杂，因为它们在黎明时在那儿玩，但是...
And with the schedules sometimes it is complicated because they play there at dawn, but ...
Y con los horarios a veces se complica porque juegan ahí de madrugada, pero...
有时，如果我们第二天不训练，而我会留下来看一些游戏。
Sometimes if we didn't train the next day and that I stay to see some games.
A veces si al otro día no entrenábamos y eso me quedo a ver algunos partiditos.
在罗萨里奥·纽维尔（Rosario Newell）和你的妻子那里，他们如何带她。
And in Rosario Newell there with your wife how they take her.
y en Rosario Newell ahí con tu mujer cómo la llevan.
是的，我们已经从那里开始了。
Yes, we already have it from there.
Sí, ya lo tenemos de ahí.
那是什么都没有发生的。
That's, nothing happens.
Ya está, no pasa nada.
游戏会一起看吗？
Do the games look together?
¿Miran los partidos juntos?
那场比赛会一起看吗？
Does that game look together?
¿Ese partido se mira juntos?
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
我有来自纽厄尔的朋友。
I have friends who are from Newell's.
Tengo amigos que son de Newell's.
我们总是在家里看到它们，经典。
We always see them at home, the classics.
También los vemos en casa siempre, los clásicos.
SE犹太人。
Se Jews.
Se joden.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
那些赢得赢得哪支球队的女孩？
And the girls who won to see what team are they?
¿Y las nenas de quién se impuso para ver de qué equipo son?
最大的是引起我的愤怒，并告诉我这就像纽厄尔的母亲，但没有来自Atlético。
And the biggest throws my anger and tells me that it is like Newell's mother, but nothing is from Atlético.
Y la más grande me tira la bronca y me dice que es como con la madre de Newell, pero nada, son del Atlético.
三人在这里生长到法院，他们遭受了Atlético的困扰。
The three grew here to the court, they suffer from Atlético.
Las tres crecieron acá yendo a la cancha, sufren por el Atlético.
看看我在手机上的消息数量，每个人都想知道这个消息。
Look at the amount of messages I have on the cell phone, everyone wondering about the news.
Mira la cantidad de mensajes que tengo en el celular, todos preguntándome por la noticia.
你告诉她还是告诉你？
Do you tell her or do you tell you?
¿La cuento o la contás vos?
我们还要多一点吗？
Do we hold it a little more?
¿La aguantamos un poco más?
不，给它，保留，保留它。
No, give it, keep it, keep it.
No, dale, contala, contala.
值得。
It's worth it.
Vale la pena.
让我告诉他。
Let me tell him.
Déjame que lo cuente.
今天在德克斯特（Dexter
Today in Dexter the hot comes out and you with how pichero you are,
Hoy en Dexter arrancó el Hot Sale y vos con lo pichero que sos,
当然，您要买东西。
Sure you're going to buy something.
seguro ya te vas a meter a comprar algo.
我要雷梅里塔（Remerita），一些鞋子。
I am for a remerita, some shoes.
Yo estoy para una remerita, unas zapas.
其他东西，有50％的折扣，人们每5次购买，一个完全免费。
Something else, there are 50% OFF and every 5 purchases that people do, one is totally free.
algo más, hay 50% off y cada 5 compras que hace la gente, una es totalmente gratis.
adexter.com.ar
而且我想，因为您是，这里有许多阿根廷人，但是您被重要目标所着火。
And I imagine, because you are, there are many Argentines here, but you were marked on fire by important goals.
Y aparte imagino, porque vos sos, hay muchos argentinos acá, pero vos quedaste marcado a fuego por goles importantes.
您会感到特别的人。
You feel a love of special people.
Sentís un cariño de la gente especial.
我们在阿根廷看到的...
What we see in Argentina ...
Lo que nosotros vemos en Argentina...
这就是您和莱蒂人的特殊联系的人。
That is what happens with you and the people of the Lety, who have a special connection with them.
que es lo que pasa con vos y la gente de la Lety, que tenés una conexión especial con ellos.
我不知道为了实现重要目标，记忆是否这么多年。
I do not know if for important goals, for the memory, for so many years.
No sé si por goles importantes, por el recuerdo, por tantos años.
您觉得还是像您在俱乐部历史上被火着的那样？
Do you feel that or is it like you were marked on fire in the history of the club?
¿Vos lo sentís eso o es como que quedaste marcado a fuego en la historia del club?
是的，我总是在这里说...
Yes, I always said here ...
Sí, yo siempre dije que acá...
它不仅是为了目标，而且很重要，而且对...
It has been valued not only for the goals, that is important, but for ...
se me ha valorado no solo por los goles, es importante eso, sino por...
我所做的努力和工作。
for the effort and work that I do.
por el esfuerzo y el trabajo que yo hago.
碰到我的几分钟，有10分钟，是60岁，是90，我进入并尝试
The minutes that touch me, have 10 minutes, be 60, be 90, I enter and try to
los minutos que me toquen, me toquen 10 minutos, sean 60, sean 90, yo entro y trato de
留下一切，我保留任何帮助团队的东西，人们一直对其进行了很多珍视和感觉。
Leaving everything, I keep anything to help the team and that people have always valued it a lot and feels.
De dejar todo, no me guardo nada para ayudar al equipo y eso la gente siempre me lo ha valorado muchísimo y se siente.
因为您知道自己的感觉很特别，而且看不到很多球员比即将进入
Because you know what you feel with you that it is special and you don't see many players than if you are substitious when you are about to enter
porque sabes que se siente con vos que es especial y no se ve muchos jugadores que si sos suplente cuando estás por entrar
人们说，天使进入。
People say, well, Angel enters.
La gente dice, bueno, entra Ángel.
会发生一些事情。
Something will happen.
Algo va a pasar.
几分钟后，它有时会显示。
In a few minutes it shows sometimes.
En pocos minutos se nota a veces.
去年几乎让我感动了我...
This last year has practically touched me ...
Este último año prácticamente me ha tocado...
那，我今年有一个小的派对，总是...
That, I had a little starting party this year and always ...
Eso, tuve poquito partido de titular este año y siempre...
在许多重要的游戏中，我在下半场留下了一些目标或一些帮助。
In many important games I have left in the second half and helped with some goal or some assistance.
en muchos partidos importantes he salido en el segundo tiempo y he ayudado con algún gol o alguna asistencia.
这样，就像人们有那种记忆一样。
So that, like people have that memory.
Entonces eso, como que la gente tiene ese recuerdo.
您是否珍视它或不到达您？
And do you value it or do not reach you?
¿Y vos lo valorás o no te alcanza?
不，是的，我重视一切，这就是为什么我一直与...交谈...
No, yes, I value everything, that's why I've always talked to ...
No, sí, yo valoro todo, por eso siempre he hablado con...
有了乔罗，我已经告诉他，我会杀死自己在努力比赛，如果我呆在这里，那就是参加比赛。
With the cholo and I have told him, I kill myself working to play, if I stay here it is to compete.
con el Cholo y le he dicho, yo me mato trabajando para jugar, si me quedo acá es para competir.
我可以帮助团队，如果我是持有人或我是替代者，我可以在您的决定后参加比赛。
I can help the team and I can play after your decision if I am a holder or I am a substitute.
que puedo ayudar al equipo y puedo jugar después de tu decisión si soy titular o soy suplente.
显然，当一个人不玩时，他会生气。
Obviously when one does not play he gets angry.
Obvio que cuando uno no juega se enoja.
但是，我试图改变它在任何几分钟内进入时的积极性。
But I try to transform it that it is positive for when it enters, in any minutes.
pero trato de ese enojo transformarlo en que sea positivo para cuando entra, en los minutos que sea.
用所有力量输入。
Enter with all the force.
entrar con toda la fuerza.
心态，因为您如何做并要求您在必须开始时不要卷曲
mentality then because how do you do and ask you not to curl when you have to start
mentalidad entonces porque cómo hacés y te pregunto para no enroscarte cuando te toca ser titular
并执行您输入的事情，您可以做一个目标，也可以发生一些事情。
And do what you do, that you enter and you can do a goal or something will happen.
y hacer lo que haces vos, que entrás y podés hacer un gol o va a pasar algo.
集中精力并不容易，也就是说，心态很重要。
It is not easy to be focused, that is, the mentality is important.
No es fácil estar enfocado, es decir, la mentalidad es importante.
信念。
The conviction.
La convicción.
完全，是的。
Totally, yes.
Totalmente, sí.
这非常困难。
It is very difficult.
Es muy difícil.
我说很多话，我已经说了，好吧...
I speak it a lot, I have spoken it, well ...
Yo lo hablo mucho, lo he hablado, bueno...
和他在一起，我的家人，男孩们在这里。
With him, with my family, with the boys here.
con él, con mi familia, con los chicos acá.
我告诉他们，一周过去了，我来训练。
I tell them, the week passes, I came to train.
Yo les digo, pasa la semana, venía a entrenar.
而且您知道您不会成为入门者。
And you know you are not going to be a starter.
y ya sabes que no vas a ser titular.
那是非常强壮的头，这并不容易，我多次发生我的脑海
that being very strong head, which is not easy, that many times happens to me that I get down
que estar muy fuerte de cabeza, que no es fácil, que muchas veces me pasa que me vengo abajo
但是，当这种情况发生在我身上时，要迅速实现并训练自己，从事更多工作。
But well, when that happens to me to realize quickly and put myself to train, to work more.
Pero bueno, cuando me pasa eso trato de darme cuenta rápido y de ponerme a entrenar, a trabajar más.
而且我知道，如果我有20分钟或25分钟，我就必须去死以帮助团队。
And I know that if I have 20 minutes or 25 I have to go to death to help the team.
Y sé que si tengo 20 minutos o 25 tengo que entrar a muerte para ayudar al equipo.
这是信任。
It is trust.
Es confianza.
也就是说，我有20分钟，我必须相信，在那20分钟内，我必须改变一些事情。
That is, I have 20 minutes and I have to have the confidence that in those 20 minutes something I have to change.
O sea, tengo 20 minutos y tengo que tener la confianza de que en esos 20 minutos algo tengo que cambiar.
是的，完全。
Yes, yes, totally.
Sí, sí, totalmente.
您必须信任，有些会成为并尝试有所作为。
You have to trust and that some will be and try to make a difference.
Tienes que confiar y que alguna te va a quedar y tratar de marcar la diferencia.
您是否已重新连接Simeone的愚蠢或Simeone的需求？
Are you recontinued to Simeone's follies or Simeone's demand?
¿Estás recontra acostumbrado a las locuras de Simeone o a la exigencia de Simeone?
你喜欢那个需求吗？
Do you like that demand?
¿Te gusta esa exigencia?
是的，事实是，实际上已经有很多年了...
Yes, the truth is, there are already so many years that practically ...
Sí, la verdad que sí, ya son tantos años que prácticamente...
他认识我，我认识他。
He as he knows me, I know him.
Él como me conoce a mí, yo lo conozco a él.
他知道我什么时候生气，何时有动力。
He knows when I am angry, when I am motivated.
Él sabe cuando yo estoy enojado, cuando estoy motivado.
他几乎每天都在看到我们很多年，我们彼此认识很多。
He practically sees us every day, many years, we know each other a lot.
prácticamente nos ve todos los días, muchos años, nos conocemos mucho.
我不知道，您记得任何需求情况的轶事，我不知道的人对他有何标记？
And what anecdote you, I don't know, capable that you remember any situation of demand, of him who, I don't know, has marked you?
¿Y qué anécdota te, no sé, capaz que te acuerdas de alguna situación de exigencia, de locura de él que, no sé, te haya marcado?
在游戏中穿着服装的演讲。
A talk in a costume, in a game.
una charla en un vestuario, en un partido.
不，是的，有成千上万，但是不，事实是...
No, yes, there are thousands, but no, the truth is that ...
No, sí, hay miles, pero no, la verdad es que...
最让我惊讶的是，我一直说的是我生活的激情。
What surprises me most and that I always say is the passion with which he lives.
Lo que más me sorprende y que siempre lo digo es la pasión con la que vive.
不仅比赛，而且训练。
Not only the matches, but the training.
No solo los partidos, sino los entrenamientos.
我们在周日参加比赛，星期一在那里。
We played on Sunday and on Monday is there.
Jugamos el domingo y ya el lunes está encima ahí.
它永远不会放松，您永远不会接受安静的训练。
It never relaxes, you never have a quiet training.
No se relaja nunca, no tiene un entrenamiento tranquilo nunca.
而且它也不会掉下来，因为它在这里也很勇敢，你输了，你在他妈的。
And it does not fall either, because it is also brave here, you lose and you are fucking.
Y no se cae tampoco, porque es bravo también acá, perdés y te vas jodiendo.
而且您赚钱，这就是成为领导者，永远不会从那里看到的一切
And you earn and that's how to be a leader and never fall what we see from there we are always
y ganas y está bien cómo hacer para ser líder y no caerse nunca lo que vemos de allá nosotros que está siempre
好的。
GOOD.
Bien.
这是关于进展多么糟糕的事情。
It is about, no matter how bad it is going forward.
Que trata de, por más que esté mal, va para adelante.
是的，是的，是的。
Yes, yes, yes.
Sí, sí, sí.
好吧，那是...
Well, that's the ...
Bueno, eso es la...
这就是为什么这个团队也有很多年的原因
That is why there are so many years on this team too, competing
por eso está tantos años en este equipo también, compitiendo
每年对阵巴塞罗那和皇家马德里
Every year against Barcelona and Real Madrid that we try to
todos los años contra Barcelona y Real Madrid que todos los años lo tratamos de
要做，这非常困难。
to do, which is very difficult.
de hacer, que es muy difícil.
今年他们非常接近，如果罚款没有能力
This year they were very close and if that penalty was not capable of
Este año estuvieron muy cerca y si no estaba ese penal capaz que
故事改变了。
The story changed.
cambió la historia.
您看到了多少次？
How many times did you see it?
¿Cuántas veces lo viste?
他们看到了吗？
Did they see it?
¿Lo vieron?
你清楚发生了什么吗？
Are you clear what happened?
¿Tenés claro qué pasó?
甚至朱利安都知道。
It is even Julian knows.
Es que ni Julián sabe.
我们总是说话，主题出来，他说，我觉得我没有两次触摸她。
We always talk and the subject comes out and he says, I feel that I not touched her twice.
Hablamos siempre y sale el tema y dice, yo siento que no la toqué de dos veces.
我们也是如此，对我们来说，必须取消目标。
We the same, for us that goal had to be canceled.
Nosotros igual, para nosotros no se tenía que haber anulado ese gol.
他们决定这样，这对我们来说是不幸的，我们不得不呆在外面。
They decided like that and it was bad luck for us and we had to stay out.
Lo decidieron así y fue mala suerte para nosotros y tuvimos que quedar afuera.
我把你带出足球一秒钟，因为几天前发生了什么事，你的视频似乎在记住。
I take you out of football for a second because something happened a few days ago and videos of yours appeared remembering.
Te saco del fútbol por un segundo porque pasó algo hace pocos días y aparecieron videos tuyos recordando.
因为Pabba Francisco和Pabba Francisco去世对您来说非常重要，因为他已做出确认。
Because Pabba Francisco and Pabba Francisco died was very important for you because he made your confirmation.
porque falleció el Pabba Francisco y el Pabba Francisco fue muy importante para vos porque hizo tu confirmación.
您是如何实现新闻的？
How did you live the news?
¿Cómo viviste la noticia?
是什么产生了你？
What generated you?
¿Qué te generó?
你能对他说些什么？
What can you say about him?
¿Qué podés decir de él?
事实是我有点意识，这已经很认真。
The truth is that I was a bit aware, which was already serious.
La verdad es que estaba un poco enterado, que estaba grave ya.
我在战斗。
That I was fighting.
que la estaba ahí peleando.
是的，这是非常可悲的消息。
Yes, it was very sad news.
Sí, fue una noticia muy triste.
对于所有阿根廷人，我看到了照片和视频。
For all the Argentines, I saw the photo and the video that came out.
para todos los argentinos, sí vi la foto y el video ese que salió.
那是他们在圣洛伦佐（San Lorenzo）开设教堂的时候。
It was when they opened the chapel in San Lorenzo.
Fue cuando inauguraron la capilla en San Lorenzo.
在那儿分享那一刻的命运，他在两年里认为他们选择了他作为教皇，没有什么是...
The fate of sharing that moment there and he at two years I think they chose him as Pope and nothing was ...
la suerte de compartir ese momento ahí con él y él a los dos años creo que lo eligieron como papa y nada fue...
我一直从他那里得到的记忆非常好。
A memory that I always had from him very nice.
Un recuerdo que siempre tuve de él muy lindo.
现在，教皇多么难以置信...
Now, how incredible the Pope ...
Ahora, qué increíble que el papa...
他刚刚和你一起去过那里，他是你扮演你的球队的粉丝。
that he has just been there with you and that he is a fan of the team in which you played you.
que justo haya estado ahí con vos y que sea hincha del equipo en el que jugabas vos.
您还记得足球评论吗？
Do you remember a football comment that made you or not?
¿Te acordás de un comentario futbolero que te hizo o no?
不，不，因为我14岁，我还是个男孩。
No, no, because there I was 14 years old, I was a boy.
No, no, porque ahí yo tenía 14 años, era chico.
我记得那天他们告诉我，那些被确认的人，养老金男孩给了我们。
I remember that day they had told me that those who were confirmed and that, the pension boys gave us.
Me acuerdo que ese día me habían dicho que a los que les faltaban confirmadas y eso, los chicos de la pensión nos dieron a decir.
我们不去上学，我们呆在那里。
that we were not going to school, that we stayed there.
que no íbamos a ir al colegio, que nos quedáramos ahí.
那个牧师来了，他是圣洛伦佐的粉丝。
that a priest was coming who was a fan of San Lorenzo.
que iba a venir un cura que era hincha de San Lorenzo.
没什么，我遇到了他。
And nothing, I met him.
Y nada, fue que lo conocí.
然后，当他已经是教皇时，您没有去梵蒂冈吗？
And then you didn't go to the Vatican when he was already Pope?
¿Y después no fuiste al Vaticano cuando ya era papa?
因为当Sanon获得冠军时，...但是...
Because when Sanon gets champion some were, but ...
Porque cuando Sanon se sale campeón algunos fueron, pero...
不，我不是。
No, I wasn't.
No, no fui.
因为我最近经营。
Because I was recently operated.
Porque yo estaba recién operado.
我进入了解放者的决赛。
I got to the final of the Liberators.
Yo llegué a la final de la Libertadores.
在那里，我在罗萨里奥（Rosario）住了几天。
And there I stayed a few days in Rosario.
y ahí me quedé unos días en Rosario.
您在注释的几个部分中命名了女儿。
You named your daughters in several parts of the note.
Nombraste a tus hijas en varias partes de la nota.
与您可以给他们的生活相比，这种对比非常好。
The contrast is very great with the life that you could give them.
El contraste es muy grande con la vida que vos le pudiste dar a ellas.
有你童年的女孩。
of girls with what was your childhood.
de chicas con lo que fue tu niñez.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
他们是两个不同的世界。
They are two different worlds.
Son dos mundos diferentes.
事实是，我试图去罗萨里奥（Rosario）接受它。
The truth is, I try to go to Rosario to take it.
La verdad que sí, trato de cuando puedo ir para Rosario llevarla.
她知道，在我长大的附近。
There she knows, in the neighborhood where I grew up.
allá que ella conozca, en el barrio donde yo me crecí.
我长大的地方，表明现实...
Where I grew up, show that reality that ...
donde me crié, mostrarle esa realidad también que...
他们活着，好吧，他们总是问我的事情，这让他们感到惊讶。
That they live it and well, they always ask me things and that are surprised.
que lo vivan y bueno, siempre me preguntan cosas y eso se sorprenden.
但是，他们也已经学习了，这很好。
But well, it's good that they already learn it too.
Pero bueno, está bueno que ya lo aprendan también.
他们与我们的人感到惊讶，当那里时，他们应该每半米阻止您。
They surprise us with people and when there, there they should stop you every half meter.
Nos sorprenden con la gente y cuando allá, pues allá te deben parar cada medio metro.
在这里，人们的生活也有所不同。
And here maybe people live it differently.
Y acá quizá la gente lo vive de manera diferente.
他们如何把那个爸爸停在每个角落？
How do they take that dad are stopped in each corner?
¿Cómo se toman ellas que al papá lo paren en cada esquina?
当我们去罗萨里奥（Rosario）或附近，人们变得疯狂时，这会更加疯狂。
It is more madness when we go to Rosario or the neighborhood and people go crazy.
Ya es más locura cuando vamos a Rosario o al barrio y la gente se vuelve loca.
而且由于有一些习惯，但这是另一回事，另一个现实。
And as there is a little customary, but here is something else, another reality.
y como que está un poquito acostumbrada, pero acá es otra cosa, otra realidad.
但是他喜欢它，他喜欢为人们服务。
But he likes it, he likes to serve people.
Pero le gusta, le gusta que atienda a la gente.
最大的总是告诉我，他意识到一切，我们就是这样行走的。
The biggest always tells me, he realizes everything, we are walking like this.
La más grande siempre me dice, se da cuenta de todo, vamos caminando así.
那里有一些孩子，爸爸，那些孩子在看着你。
And there are some children there, Dad, those children are looking at you.
Y hay unos niños ahí que dicen, papá, esos niños te están mirando.
他们想要一张照片之类的东西，在我看来。
They want a photo or something, it seems to me.
Quieren una foto o algo, me parece.
他要我去。
As he wants me to go.
Como que quiere que yo lo vaya.
但是，对于不想要任何东西的女儿和爸爸，他们正要看着我。
But for daughters and dad who don't want anything, they are looking at me just and come.
Pero para hijas y papá que no quieren nada, me están mirando nomás y vienen.
你看到我告诉你的吗？
Did you see what I told you?
¿Viste que te dije?
您要带到您出生的附近什么？
And what do you take to the neighborhood where you were born?
¿Y qué le llevas al barrio donde naciste vos?
牧场？
To the pasture?
¿Al potrero?
是的，是的，拉斯·弗洛雷斯（Las Flores）社区，我在罗萨里奥（Rosario）。
Yes, yes, the Las Flores neighborhood, I there in Rosario.
Sí, sí, el barrio Las Flores, yo ahí en Rosario.
我让我的祖母住在那里。
I have my grandmother living there.
Tengo a mi abuela viviendo ahí.
每当我们度过几个假期时，都会来探望他们。
Every time we have a few holidays, come on and visit them.
Cada vez que tenemos pocas vacaciones, vamos y las visitamos.
当您认为自己出生的地方，住在哪里，您必须战斗时会产生什么？
What generates you when you think where you were born, where you lived, did you have to fight?
¿Qué te genera cuando te pones a pensar dónde naciste vos, dónde viviste, vos lo tuviste que luchar?
也就是说，您现在所处的位置，因为一切也发生了，有能力没有意识到，一年您会赢得一件事，足球。
And where you are now, that is, because everything also happens, capable do not realize, one year you will win a thing, football.
y dónde estás ahora, es decir, porque también pasa todo rápido, capaz no te das cuenta, un año ganás una cosa, fútbol.
事实是，您去了一个非常困难的地方。
And the truth is that you went out to a very difficult place.
Y la verdad es que saliste a un lugar muy difícil.
离开那个地方并到达自己的位置非常困难。
It is very difficult to get out of that place and get where you are.
Es muy difícil salir de ese lugar y llegar a donde estás.
您不能经常考虑一下，还是您不再标准化的东西？
Can't you think about it every so often or is it something you no longer normalized?
¿No te lo podés pensar cada tanto o es algo que ya no normalizaste?
事实是，主要的事情使我感到自豪。
The truth is that the main thing fills me with pride.
La verdad es que lo principal me llena de orgullo.
如果我离开那里，到达我所达到的目标。
If I got out of there and get to what I have reached.
de haber salido de ahí y llegar a lo que he llegado.
我所取得的成就是使我的家人摆脱贫困，因为这是现实，我们不必吃饭。
What I have achieved is to get my family out of poverty because it is a reality, we did not have to eat.
Lo que he conseguido es sacar de la pobreza a mi familia porque es una realidad, nosotros no teníamos para comer.
我们是10个兄弟，然后当我父亲去世时，我10岁，
We were 10 brothers, then when my dad passed away, that I was 10 years old,
Eramos 10 hermanos, después cuando mi papá falleció, que yo tenía 10 años,
我妈妈一个人，我们每天吃一次，所以我们吃了，然后...
My mother was alone and we ate once a day, so we ate, then ...
quedó mi mamá sola y comíamos una vez al día, así comíamos, entonces...
为了实现这一点，现在感谢上帝，我们不会错过任何事情。
To live that, that now, thank God, we don't miss anything.
a vivir eso, a que ahora, gracias a Dios, no nos falte nada.
他们是两个完全不同的事情，让我感到自豪。
They are two totally different things and fill me with pride.
Son dos cosas totalmente diferentes y me llenan de orgullo.
我不经常考虑，但是...
I don't think about it, very often, but ...
No lo pienso mucho, muy seguido, pero...
但是，是的，这很好。
But yes, it is good.
Pero sí, está buen.
你照顾你们所有人的老太太。
Your old woman who took care of all of you.
Tu vieja que se hizo cargo de todos ustedes.
是的，是的，我的老妇。
Yes, yes, my old woman.
Sí, sí, mi vieja.
和你很小的人。
And you who were very small.
Y ustedes que eran muy chiquitos.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
当我父亲去世时，我当时十岁了，12岁时我已经去了布宜诺斯艾利斯。
I was 10 years old when my dad died and at 12 I already went to Buenos Aires.
Yo tenía 10 años cuando falleció mi papá y a los 12 años ya me fui a Buenos Aires.
在养老金中，我几乎没有赢了，他们给了我一个迪姆，我妈妈把它给了他。
And there in the pension, how little I won, that they gave me a per diem, my mother gave it to him.
Y ahí en la pensión, lo poquito que ganaba yo, que me daban un viático, se lo daba mi mamá.
他们必须选择什么时候吃饭。
And they had to choose at what time they ate.
y tenían que elegir en qué momento del día comían.
是的，是的，总是在中午。
Yes, yes, always at noon.
Sí, sí, siempre al mediodía.
夜晚什么都没有。
Of the night nothing.
De la noche ya nada.
而且很难入睡，对吗？
And it was difficult to sleep, right?
Y era difícil dormir, ¿no?
是的，总是。
Yes, always.
Sí, sí, siempre.
这是一切最有价值的。
That is the most valuable of everything.
Eso es lo más valorable de todo.
我不知道你的兄弟是否提醒你。
I don't know if your brothers remind you.
No sé si tus hermanos te lo recuerdan.
是的，很多。
Yes, much.
Sí, mucha cosa.
当我们聚在一起时，我们开始聊天。
We started chatting when we got together and that.
Por ahí nos poníamos a charlar cuando nos juntábamos y eso.
我们小时候生活的东西，我们要问，我们要去...
Things we lived as a boy, we were going to ask, we were going to ...
cosas que vivíamos de chico, nosotros íbamos a pedir, íbamos a...
通向中心的出租车门，我们要和母亲一起出售玫瑰，母亲带我们。
Open taxi doors to the center, we were going to sell roses with my mother, my mother took us.
abrir puertas de taxi al centro, íbamos a vender rosas con mi mamá, mi mamá nos llevaba.
很多事情，我们祖母也走了
Many things, with my grandmother we have also walked
muchas cosas, con mi abuela también hemos caminado
公里和公里要去回家，我们总是记得所有这些。
Kilometer and kilometer to go to ask home and that we always remember all those things.
kilómetro y kilómetro para ir a pedir casa por casa y eso siempre nos acordamos de todas esas cosas.
没什么，我们也以幸福记得它，因为那时非常...
And nothing, we remember it with happiness too, because at that time it was very ...
Y nada, lo recordamos con felicidad también, porque en ese momento era muy...
我们对我们的工作很少感到满意。
We were happy with how little we had.
Éramos felices con lo poco que teníamos.
因此，您是否充满快乐，幸福地记得吗？
And so, do you remember with joy, with happiness?
Y así todo, ¿lo recordás con alegría, con felicidad?
是的，完全。
Yes, totally.
Sí, totalmente.
您看到这与您的幸福或悲伤无关。
You saw that it has nothing to do with what you have with how happy you are or how sad.
Viste que no tiene nada que ver lo que tenés con lo feliz que sos o lo triste.
也许他们也不知道，对吗？
Maybe they were not so aware either, right?
Quizás tampoco eran tan conscientes, ¿no?
不，那是男孩，去帮助你的母亲。
No, that is boy and goes to help your mother.
No, eso es chico y va para ayudar a tu mamá.
我妈妈带我们去，我们要去，我们在我们中间竞争，看看谁加入了更多的钱来给他。
My mom took us, we were going and we competed among us to see who joined more money to give him.
Mi mamá nos llevaba, íbamos y nosotros competíamos entre nosotros a ver quién juntaba más plata para darle.
我们告诉母亲。
We told the mother.
A la mamá, le decíamos nosotros.
然后，巴里斯在下午的一些牧场上踢足球。
And then Parías to play football in the afternoon in some pasture.
Y después parías a jugar al fútbol por la tarde en algún potrero.
我们总是在placita中玩，好吧，我总是对我父亲有一个记忆
We play in the placita always and well I always have a memory of my dad that
jugamos en la placita siempre y bueno tengo un recuerdo siempre de mi papá que
那说了一切，我将要达到第一个，我总是对我说话。
That said everything, that I was going to get to the first, and I always spoke to me.
que le decía todo, que yo iba a llegar a la primera, y a mí también me hablaba siempre.
他让我在瘦腿上这样的按摩。
He made me massage like this in the skinny legs.
Me hacía masaje así en las piernas flaquitas.
我告诉自己你有什么大虾。
I told myself what prawn you have.
Yo me decía qué gamba que tenés.
他告诉我，您将首先到达，您将帮助您的母亲和兄弟。
He told me, you will arrive first, you will help your mother and your brothers.
Me decía, vas a llegar primera, vas a ayudar a tu mamá y a tus hermanos.
我不会，我不会活下去，但是你要这样做。
I'm not going to be, I'm not going to live that, but you're going to do it.
Yo no voy a estar, yo no voy a vivir eso, pero vos lo vas a hacer.
我看着他说，你在告诉我什么？
And I looked at him saying, what are you telling me?
Y yo lo miraba diciendo, ¿qué me estás diciendo?
那很小，我九岁。
That was small, I was nine years old.
Ese era chiquito, tenía nueve años.
当他去世时，我总是把那个。
And when he died, I always had that in my head.
Y cuando él falleció, eso lo tenía siempre en mi cabeza.
您想实现他的梦想。
You wanted to fulfill his dream.
Querías cumplir el sueño de él.
这使您能够考虑实现老人告诉您的一切。
That gives you strength to think about fulfilling what your old man told you.
que te da fuerza a pensar en cumplir lo que te ha dicho tu viejo.
每隔一段时间，您都会想到他，您都记得他，您与他交谈。
And every so often you think of him, you remember him, you talk to him.
y cada tanto pensás en él, te acuerdas de él, hablás con él.
现在我和母亲做了其他事情，因为两年前她去世了。
And now I do something else with my mother, because two years ago she died.
Y ahora hago algo más con mi mamá, porque hace dos años que falleció.
仅在4月6日。
Just April 6 has been spent.
Justo hace el 6 de abril pasaron dos años.
现在我的老妇是最近的，我和她一起做。
Now that my old woman is more recent, I do it with her.
Ahora que es más reciente lo de mi vieja, lo hago con ella.
当时，您父亲已经看到您了，您的腿很瘦，已经在Potrero时代了。
And it was already at that time that your dad saw you, that you had the skinny legs, already in the Potrero eras good.
Y ya era en esa época que tu papá te veía, que tenías las piernitas flacas, ya en el potrero eras bueno.
是的，它是在VAO中得分的，几乎在那里指出。
Yes, it was scored in the vao and noted almost there.
Sí, se anotaba en el vao y se anotaba casi ahí.
你走得很好。
And you walked well.
Y andabas bien.
很好，它得分了。
Very well, it was scored.
Muy bien, se anotaba.
您一生什么时候意识到...？
When your life did you realize ...?
¿En qué momento de tu vida te diste cuenta...?
我的老人告诉我，我想他会实现的，你意识到，我会踢足球，他们会付给我踢足球。
What my old man told me, I think he will fulfill, that you realized and well, I will play football and they will pay me to play football.
Lo que me dijo mi viejo, creo que se va a cumplir, que te diste cuenta y bueno, voy a jugar al fútbol y me van a pagar por jugar al fútbol.
当我开始在Atlético玩第一年或第二年。
When I started playing the first or second year here in Atlético.
cuando empecé a jugar el primer o segundo año acá en el Atlético.
我仍然觉得没有什么或多或少地从这里开始的合同开始，说不，这还不够。
That I still felt that nothing was just starting here with a contract there more or less and said no, this is not yet enough for the end.
que todavía sentía que nada, recién estaba arrancando acá con un contrato ahí más o menos y decía no, esto todavía no me alcanza para el final.
每当我进入法院时，我都想起了我们的时代...
And every time I entered a court I remembered the times we were ...
y cada vez que entraba a una cancha me acordaba de las veces que íbamos...
要求中心，出售玫瑰，
To ask the center, to sell roses,
a pedir al centro, a vender rosas,
我们从雨中饿了，我们弄湿了，所有这些都给了我...
That we were hungry, from the rain, that we got wet, all that gave me strength to ...
de que pasábamos hambre, de la lluvia, que nos mojábamos, todo eso me daba fuerza para...
去法院吃东西，不要以最好的方式得到充分的喂养
To go to the court and eat them and not be well fed in the best way
para salir a la cancha y comérmelas y no estar bien alimentado de la mejor manera
但是我们在圣洛伦佐（San Lorenzo）的营养师总是...
But the nutritionist we had in San Lorenzo always ...
pero la nutricionista que teníamos en San Lorenzo siempre...
他告诉我，就像在营养不良中，他告诉我，他们给了我更多
He told me, like, in malnutrition he told me, they gave me more
me decía, gusta, en desnutrición me decía, me daban más
更多食物，每个人都去旅行，他们给了我两个。
More food, each one gave a trip and they gave me two.
más comida, cada uno le daba una viandita y a mi me daban dos.
因为那是我已经很瘦了。
Because it was that I was already skinny, skinny.
Porque era que yo ya venía flaco, flaco.
将来不是为您调理吗？
And wasn't it conditioning you in the future?
¿Y no te fue condicionando a futuro?
一旦接近，我就开始玩reer，已经开始了。
Once I was close, I started playing reer, there it was already beginning.
Una vez que ya estaba cerca, empecé a jugar al reservo, ahí ya empezaba.
感觉更好。
To feel better.
a sentirme mejor.
阿隆索（Alonso）有了那个营养学计划，您提出了一点。
Alonso, with that nutritionist plan, you raised a little.
Alonso, con ese plan de la nutricionista, levantaste un poquito.
是的，是的，因为它很瘦。
Yes, yes, because it was very skinny.
Sí, sí, porque era muy flaquito.
然后，我不知道，在圣洛伦佐（San Lorenzo）或帕尔顿（Bausa Palton）中到达第一个。
Then reach the first, I don't know, in that San Lorenzo or in the Bausa Palton.
después llegar a la primera, no sé, en aquel San Lorenzo o en el Paltón Bausa.
他没有注意到做好准备的男孩的身体差异。
He did not notice the physical difference of boys who were more prepared.
No notaba la diferencia física de chicos que estaban más preparados.
他们吃得更好，您没有注意到吗？
Had they eaten better and did you not notice?
¿Habían comido mejor y vos o no notabas?
不，我没有注意到它，因为我只是注意到它很快。
No, I didn't notice it because I just noticed that it was fast.
No, ahí no la notaba porque solo notaba que era rápido.
然后，大法庭的Juárez和San Lorenzo速度迅速，告诉我熬夜前进。
Then, Juárez and San Lorenzo of the big court and I with the speed and told me stay up and go forward.
Entonces, Juárez y San Lorenzo de la cancha grande y yo con la velocidad y me decían quedate arriba y andá para adelante.
当我拥有的时候，两位技术人员也是如此。
And the patón when I had it, the two technicians the same.
y el patón cuando lo tuve, los dos técnicos igual.
他们告诉我抓住球，向前朝前。
They told me to grab the ball and face forward.
Me decían agarrar la pelota y encarar para adelante.
好像它在您附近的广场上。
As if it were in your neighborhood square.
Como si estuviera en la plaza de tu barrio.
我喜欢那个。
And I loved that.
Y yo me encantaba eso.
随着我的感觉很快，我注意到了差异。
And with what I felt fast, I noticed the difference.
Y con lo que me sentía que era rápido, notaba la diferencia.
我在想你说的一切，你到了primera，它们出现了
I was thinking about everything you said, you get to Primera, they appear
Estaba pensando en todo lo que contaste, llegas a primera, aparecen
一个非常重要的转移的可能性，当您获得主题时，一定是
The possibility of a very important transfer and when you get the theme of the heart must have been
la posibilidad de una transferencia importantísima y cuando te sale el tema del corazón debe haber sido
我重新考虑是否可以给予我梦dream以求的一切。
I rethink whether all that I had dreamed could be given or not.
replantearte si todo eso que había soñado se podía dar o no.
是的，但是那一刻我也告诉并说...
Yes, but well at that moment I have also told and said that ...
Sí, pero bueno en ese momento también lo he contado y he dicho que...
好，这是我的18年发生在我身上，他们即将运作，我和两个人在一起，只在纽约。
Good, with 18 years this happened to me, they were about to operate, I was with Agustín, the two, only in New York.
que bueno, con 18 años me pasó esto, me estaban por operar, estaba con Agustín, los dos, solo en Nueva York.
我说，好吧，是的...
And I say, well, yes ...
Y le digo, bueno, si...
如果我必须死，我和父亲一起去，我告诉他。
If I have to die I go with my dad, I told him.
Si me tengo que morir me voy con mi papá, le dije.
我非常想念他，我的一个兄弟死了。
I missed him very much and one of my brothers who had died.
Lo extrañaba mucho también y a uno de mis hermanos que había fallecido.
没什么，我和他们一起去。
And nothing, I go with them.
Y nada, yo me voy con ellos.
Agustín说，闭嘴！
And Agustín says, shut up!
Y Agustín dice, ¡cállate!
你疯了？
Are you crazy?
¿Tú estás loco?
你怎么说？
How are you going to say that?
¿Cómo vas a decir eso?
什么都没有发生，一切进展顺利，我说，你不怕吗？
Nothing happens, everything is going well, I said, you weren't afraid?
No pasa nada, va a salir todo bien, le decía yo ¿No tenías miedo?
不，不，但我认为这是为此。
No, no, but I think it was for that.
No, no, pero creo que era por eso.
如果出错，我和爸爸一起离开。
If it goes wrong, I'm leaving with my dad.
Si sale mal, me voy con mi papá.
现在我很大，我不知道自己的想法或说了什么。
Now that I am bigger, I was not aware of what I thought or what I said.
Ahora que soy más grande, no era consciente de lo que pensaba o lo que decía.
如果您抓住您的更大，它会抓住您更多的狗屎。
If you grab you bigger, it grabs you more shit.
Si te agarra más grande, te agarra más cagazo.
当然，踢足球已经呆在第二个计划中。
Of course, playing football had stayed in a second plan.
Claro, jugar al fútbol había quedado en un segundo plan.
是的，在后台，但是一旦我也很接近，我告诉Agustín。
Yes, in the background, but once I was also close, I told Agustín.
Sí, en un segundo plano, pero ya una vez que también estaba ahí cerca, le dije a Agustín.
我想要的是再次踢足球，看看我知道如何做。
All I want is to play football again and see what I know how to do.
Yo lo único que quiero es volver a jugar al fútbol y ver lo que sé hacer.
我无法想象做其他事情，做其他事情。
I can't imagine doing anything else, working something else.
No me imagino haciendo otra cosa, trabajando otra cosa.
我想打球。
I want to play ball.
Yo quiero jugar a la pelota.
我希望一切顺利，感谢上帝，可能是那样的。
I hope everything goes well and thank God it could be like that.
Ojalá que salga todo bien y gracias a Dios pudo ser así.
他们确认我可以玩，因为除了操作之外，他们必须让您检查并确认...是的，每天他们都会让我检查，什么也没有，不...
They confirmed that I could play, because beyond the operation then they have to make you check and confirm that ... yes, every day they made me checks and nothing, no ...
confirmaron que podía jugar, pues más allá de la operación después te tienen que hacer chequeos y confirmar que... Sí, todos los días me hacían chequeos y nada, no...
3或4个月我只开始在这里训练。
3 or 4 months I started to train only here.
3 o 4 meses empecé a entrenar solo acá.
你知道我一个人在这里跑去吗？
Do you know the times I ran here alone?
¿Sabes las veces que corrí acá solo?
仅两个月的培训。
As two months training alone.
Como dos meses entrenando solo.
直到Humberto Rondona来了，只有次美国Su-20。
Until Humberto Rondona came and just the sub-American Su-20 was.
hasta que vino Humberto Rondona y justo estaba el Subamericano SU-20.
他来找我，他告诉我我想玩，我说如果我想玩，我不能忍受，我在俱乐部训练。
He came to look for me, he tells me I want to play, I say if please I want to play, I can't stand it anymore, I'm training just here at the club.
me vino a buscar, me dice quiero que juegue, digo si por favor yo quiero jugarle, no aguanto más, estoy entrenando solo acá en el club.
我不得不去俱乐部交谈，告诉米开朗基罗让我去南美比赛。
I had to go talk to the club and tell Michelangelo to let me go to play in South America.
Tuve que ir a hablar con el club y decirle a Miguel Ángel que dejárame ir a jugar en Sudamérica.
不，是医生，不知道你是否还不错。
No, it is that the doctor, who do not know if you are still well.
No, es que el doctor, que no saben si todavía estás bien.
我感觉很好，如果我发生了什么事，我会负责。
I feel good, I take charge, if something happens to me.
Yo me siento bien, yo me hago cargo, si me pasa algo me hago cargo.
他们决定放开我，幸运的是我们赢得了比赛。
And there they decided to let me go and luckily we won the tournament.
Y ahí decidieron dejarme ir y por suerte ganamos el torneo.
这是你的第一个。
It was your first.
Fue tu primer.
这是您在阿根廷国家队中的第一次出色，所有这些都在谈论您。
It was your first great appearance in the Argentine National Team, which all talked about you.
Fue tu primera gran aparición en la selección argentina esa, que hablaron todos de vos.
它到达了将近五个月，没有打球而没有碰球。
It arrived almost five months and peak without playing, without touching a ball.
Llegaba casi cinco meses y pico sin jugar, sin tocar una pelota.
事实是，回去赢得比赛并选择了最佳球员，这是一种巨大的喜悦。
The truth is that, go back to win the tournament and chose the best player, an immense joy.
La verdad que sí, volver así, ganar el torneo y me eligieron el mejor jugador, una alegría inmensa.
而且，我对这个俱乐部所感受到的爱的一部分也必须是，即，他们在一个时候信任您
And also part of the love that I felt for this club must also have been that, that is, they trusted you at a time where
y también parte del amor que sentí por este club también debe haber sido eso, o sea confiaron en vos en un momento en donde
他们本可以信任我们。
They could have trusted us.
Podrían habernos confiado.
他总是感谢亨伯托。
He always thanked Humberto.
Siempre se lo agradecía a Humberto.
他把麻烦来自布宜诺斯艾利斯来与我见面。
He took the trouble to come from Buenos Aires here to meet with me.
se tomó la molestia de venir de Buenos Aires acá a reunirse conmigo.
告诉我，我要你去，我希望你成为这支球队的队长，我们将成为冠军。
To tell me, I want you to go, I want you to be the captain of this team, we will be champions.
a decirme, quiero que vaya, quiero que seas el capitán de este equipo, vamos a ser campeones.
我告诉他一切，我想打球。
I told him everything, I wanted to play ball.
Yo le decía todo que sí, yo quería jugar a la pelota.
幸运的是进展顺利。
Luckily it went well.
Por suerte salió bien.
然后我也记得这一点，但是一次有阿根廷性爱，我认为那是决赛。
And then I remember that too, but there is the Argentine sex at one time, I think it was in the final.
Y después me acuerdo que también, pero ya está la Sexo Argentina en un momento, creo que fue en la finalísima.
我记得我认为这是一个游戏和另一场比赛之间的前提。
I remember that I think it was the pre or between one game and the other.
Yo me acuerdo que creo que fue la semana pre o entre un partido y el otro.
那怎么样？
How was that?
¿Cómo fue eso?
不，在这里，我有我在这里的疤痕的最后一点。
No, it was here, I had the last point of the scar that I have here.
No, estaba acá, tenía el último punto de la cicatriz que tengo acá.
我出来了，看到了里面，罗德里（Rodri）在这里给男孩们展示了。
I was coming out, I saw the inside and I showed the boys here, Rodri.
Se me estaba saliendo, se me veía la parte de adentro y yo le mostraba a los chicos acá, a Rodri.
狮子座，给所有男孩。
Leo, to all the boys.
a Leo, a todos los chicos.
我们在那里带伴侣，我说，不，它将离开，我将要开放。
We were there taking mate and I say, no, it is about to leave, I am about to open.
Estábamos ahí tomando mate y le digo, no, se me está por salir, se me está por abrir.
不，他抓住了头。
No, he grabs the head.
No, se agarra en la cabeza.
你疯了？
Are you crazy?
¿Vos estás loco?
他告诉我，让医生放开。
He told me, let the doctor let it go.
Me decía, avísale al doctor.
不，Ligo，因为如果我通知您，他们会送我去...
No, Ligo, because if I notify you, they will send me to ...
No, Ligo, porque si le aviso me van a mandar a...
去我家或医院。
To my house or the hospital.
a mi casa o al hospital.
我想结束。
I want to be at the end.
Yo quiero estar al final.
然后我看到，读，什么也没发生。
Then I see, read, nothing happens.
Después veo, leo, no pasa nada.
好吧，事情发生了。
Well, and things happen.
Bueno, y pasa lo de las cosas.
我完成了，第二天我会通知您，因为我正在健康地灌溉。
I finish and the next day I will notify you because I am running irrigation in my health.
finalizo y al otro día le voy a avisar porque estoy corriendo riego en mi salud.
当我到达马德里的时候，医生告诉我，你疯了吗？
And when I arrived here in Madrid, the doctor told me, are you crazy?
Y cuando llegué acá a Madrid, me dijo el doctor, ¿Vos estás loco?
他告诉我，看，如果被感染，那可能是...
And he tells me, look, if this is infected, it could be ...
Y me dice, mira, si esto se te infecta, podría ser...
你有什么开放点？
What did you have an open point?
¿Qué era lo que tenías un punto abierto?
当然，我看着里面，看着一块电线。
Of course, I looked inside, I looked a piece of wire that I have.
Claro, se me veía para adentro, se me veía un pedacito de alambre que tengo.
他们不得不再次睡觉，将其删除，然后再次缝制。
And they had to sleep again, remove that and again sew again.
y me tuvieron que dormir otra vez, quitar eso y otra vez volver a coser.
但是你想加入...是的，我不想错过那场比赛。
But you wanted to be in ... yes, I didn't want to miss that game.
Pero vos querías estar en... Sí, no me quería perder ese partido.
罚款有所不同吗？
Did the penalty vary?
¿Varió la pena?
是的，是的，显而易见，除了那个决赛。
Yes, yes, obvious, apart from that final there.
Sí, sí, obvio, aparte esa finalísima ahí.
总是，一切，我住在国家队的每一刻。
Always, everything, every moment I live in the National Team.
Siempre, todo, cada momento que vivo en la selección.
我真的很喜欢这支球队，这是我们这些年来我们生活的一切。
I really enjoy this squad, it is incredible everything we live in these years.
Lo disfruto muchísimo con este plantel que hay, es increíble todo lo que vivimos estos años.
我总是要保持心。
I'm always going to keep my heart.
Me voy a guardar siempre en mi corazón.
这就是为什么您花时间，但这很有趣。
That is why you spend time, but it was very funny.
Por esto pasas un tiempo, pero fue muy gracioso.
当您拥有国家队的第10位时，我不是狮子座，玻利维亚没有梅西。
When you had the 10th of the National Team, I was not Leo, there was no Messi in Bolivia.
Cuando tenías la 10 de la selección, no estaba Leo, no estaba Messi en Bolivia.
有人认为有些人进入...是的，我认为粉丝们被认为是华盛顿特区。
that some were thought to enter ... Yes, I think the fans were thought to be the DC.
que algunas se pensaron que entraban... Sí, creo que la hinchada se pensaba que entraban la DC.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
没事，疯狂。
Nothing, madness.
Nada, una locura.
您也开始思考的标题是因为圣洛伦佐没有杯岛。
The titles you have also started thinking because San Lorenzo had no Copa Libertadores.
Los títulos que tenés además te pusiste a pensar porque San Lorenzo no tenía Copa Libertadores.
梅西（Messi）与阿根廷国家队没有任何头衔，超出了对您的意义。
Messi had no titles with the Argentine National Team, beyond what it means for you.
Messi no tenía títulos con la selección argentina, más allá de lo que significa para vos.
但这就像您获得了许多标题
But it's like you got a number of titles
pero es como que conseguiste una cantidad de títulos
所有这些都很重要，但是这些重量很大，历史很多。
All are important, but these have a lot of weight, a lot of history.
Todos son importantes, pero estos tienen mucho peso, mucha historia.
是的，是的，事实是。
Yes, yes, the truth is.
Sí, sí, la verdad que sí.
一切都很重要。
All are important.
Todos son importantes.
这是我们为始终获得标题而努力的工作。
And it is what we work for, to get titles always.
Y es para lo que trabajamos, para conseguir títulos siempre.
好的展示，您是否有？
Good showcase you have, or not?
Buena vitrina tenés, ¿o no?
事实是。
The truth is that.
La verdad que sí.
成为世界冠军。
be world champion.
ser campeón del mundo.
发生这种情况之后，您的兄弟告诉您什么？
What did your brothers told you after that happened?
¿Qué te dijeron tus hermanos después de que se dio eso?
我们已经知道人们，我们想了解您的家人。
We already know about people, we want to know about your family.
Lo de la gente ya lo sabemos, queremos saber de tu familia.
请记住，您发生的事情以及您在男孩时告诉了什么，然后举行了世界杯。
Remember what happened to you and what you told what happened as a boy and then have the World Cup.
Acordarse de lo que te pasaba y lo que contaste que pasaba de chico y después tener la Copa del Mundo.
手之间的世界。
world between the hand.
mundo acá entre la mano.
我已经说过的，我拥有的最大记忆是我已经有了坏人。
What I have already said, the biggest memory I have of that is that I already had my bad guy.
Lo que ya lo he dicho también, el mayor recuerdo que tengo de eso es que ya la tenía mi vejita mal.
我想把她带到决赛，医生建议我不要接受它，因为
And I wanted to take her to the final and the doctors recommended that I do not take it because
y yo la quise llevar a la final y los doctores me recomendaron que no la lleve porque
我本来打算做错的飞机，这将是非常严重的。
I was going to do the plane wrong, it was going to be very serious.
le iba a hacer mal el avión, iba a ser muy grave.
我有那个荆棘无法在世界杯决赛中获得它，但到达这里...
I had that thorn of not being able to have it in the World Cup final, but arrive here ...
Me quedó esa espinita de no poder tenerla en la final del Mundial, pero llegar acá...
看到她哭泣并放了奖牌，这对我来说是最好的。
And seeing her crying and putting the medal, that was the best for me.
y verla llorando y ponerle la medalla, eso fue lo máximo para mí.
也就是说，您打了一个视频通话，几乎不能...是的，是的，在视频通话中，但是那是我到达马德里的时候，我去了他的房子...
That is, you made a video call, you could barely ... yes, yes, there in the video call, but that was when I arrived here in Madrid, I went to his house and ...
O sea, es que hiciste un videollamada, apenas pudiste... Sí, sí, ahí en el toque videollamada, pero fue cuando llegué acá a Madrid, fui a su casa y le...
我读了奖牌，开始哭泣，仅此而已。
I read the medal and began to cry and that's it.
Leí la medalla y se puso a llorar y ya está.
此外，您没有去世界。
Besides, you didn't go to the world.
Además vos no ibas al mundo.
不，不，原则上我没有走，他被排除在外。
No, no, in principle I didn't go, he had been left out.
No, no, en principio no iba, había quedado fuera.
然后，我记得那是...
And then, well, I remember that it was ...
Y después, bueno, recuerdo que estaba...
布宜诺斯艾利斯，我去了罗萨里奥，阿古斯丁告诉我
Buenos Aires and there I went to Rosario and Agustín told me
Buenos Aires y ahí me fui a Rosario y Agustín me decía
他告诉我，留下来，留下来他们会打电话给你。
Stay, stay that they will call you, he told me.
Quédate, quédate que te van a llamar, me decía.
留下来称呼你的东西。
Stay what will call you.
Quédate que te van a llamar.
我不会再说我，我要祈祷，我要去附近。
And I will call me nothing more and I'm going to pray and I'm going to the neighborhood.
Y yo nada más que me van a llamar y yo me voy a rezar y me voy al barrio.
我和妻子和女孩一起离开。
I left with my wife and girls.
me fui con mi mujer y las nenas.
第二天，他们给我打电话，给我写了罗德里，并告诉我朋友。它在哪里？
And the next day they called me and wrote me Rodri and tells me friend. Where is it?
y al otro día me llamaron y me escribió Rodri y me dice amigo ¿dónde está?
我告诉念珠，如果您不专心，因为它可能会被称为。
I tell the rosary, if you are not attentive because it may be called.
Yo le digo al Rosario, si vos no estás atento porque puede ser que te llame.
啊，好吧，给它。
Ah, well, give it.
Ah, bueno, dale.
疑问开始进入，这是真的吗？
And there the doubt began to enter, will it be true?
Y ahí empezó a entrar la duda, ¿será verdad?
没什么，一旦他们叫我，我说，很明显，我要去。
And nothing, once they called me I said, obvious, I'm going.
Y nada, una vez que me llamaron dije, obvio, voy a ir.
如果路线，飞机怎么办？
What if the route, plane?
¿Y si de ruta, avión?
是的，从罗萨里奥（Rosario）到布宜诺斯艾利斯（Buenos Aires），从布宜诺斯艾利斯（Buenos Aires）到巴西和巴西。
Yes, from Rosario to Buenos Aires, from Buenos Aires to Brazil and Brazil there.
Sí, de Rosario a Buenos Aires, de Buenos Aires a Brasil y de Brasil para allá.
极好的。
Incredible.
Increíble.
你的老女人在你的生活中意味着什么？
What does your old woman mean in your life?
¿Qué significa tu vieja en tu vida?
因为你谈论了你的老人。
Because you talked about your old man.
Porque hablaste de tu viejo.
你的老妇是什么意思？
And what does your old woman mean?
¿Y tu vieja qué significa?
一切，我妈妈，一切。
Everything, my mom, everything.
Todo, mi mamá, todo.
她是一名战士，我们总是和我的兄弟一起记得她。
She is a warrior, we always remember her with my brothers.
Es una guerrera, siempre la recordamos con mis hermanos.
...像战士一样。
... like a warrior.
...como una guerrera.
她与之抗争的东西，这三年来与癌症作斗争的事，我们看到了我们每天在那里看到她的。
What she fought, what lived these three years fighting cancer, we saw it that we saw her every day there.
Lo que luchó ella, lo que vivió estos últimos tres años luchando contra el cáncer, lo vimos nosotros que la veíamos todos los días ahí.
我告诉他，实际上将其烧毁的是一名战士。
that practically burned it inside is a warrior, I told him.
que prácticamente la quemaban por dentro es una guerrera, yo le decía.
一个人总是自私的，因为在这种情况下，我一直想拥有它。
One is always selfish, because in this case I always wanted to have it.
Uno siempre es egoísta, porque yo en este caso la quería tener siempre.
但是我看到她在床上受苦。
But I saw her I was suffering in a bed.
pero yo la veía que estaba sufriendo en una cama.
今天，我看到了它，我说他正在安息，这也让我一个人呆着。
Today I see it on the other hand and I say that he is resting in peace and that leaves me alone too.
Hoy en día lo veo de otro lado y digo que está descansando en paz y eso me deja tranquilo también.
他最终做到了，并与您的小孩子作战。
He did it in the end and fought it with you little ones.
Lo hizo en el final y la peleó con ustedes chiquitos.
是的，总是。
Yes, always.
Sí, siempre.
寿命。
Lifetime.
Toda la vida.
那是我们的战士，那是总是给我力量的那个战士。
It was our warrior and it was the one that always gave me strength.
Fue nuestra guerrera y era la que siempre me daba fuerza.
这样我也一直在战斗。
so that I keep fighting too.
para que yo siga luchando también.
每当我在那里看到我时，他告诉我，你怎么了？
Whenever I saw me there, he told me, what's wrong with you?
Siempre que me veía ahí me decía, ¿qué te pasa negrito?
他告诉我，我在那里见到你吗？
He told me, do I see you there?
Me decía, ¿te veo ahí?
他说，给他，您将进球。
He says, give him, that you are going to score a goal.
Dice, dale, dale, que vas a meter un gol.
我也想念那个。
And there I miss that too.
Y por ahí extraño eso también.
并能够在比赛结束后与他们交谈。
and be able to talk to them after the games.
y poder hablar con ellas después de los partidos.
是的，你有...
Yes, you have ...
Sí, por ahí tenés...
我当时在游戏中，我正要开始并告诉我，你好，黑人，你在哪里？
I was in a game, I was about to start and told me, Hello black, where are you?
Yo por ahí estaba en un partido, estaba por empezar y me decía, hola negro, ¿dónde estás?
他来找一些伴侣。
He came to take some mates.
Venía a tomar unos mates.
是的，要玩。
Yes, for playing.
Sí, por jugar.